Guide to the Thomas Andrew Bailey Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Papers, 1927-1967; Series 1
  - Correspondence, G-L, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Leopold, Richard W., 1965 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, L-P, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Leebrick, K. C., 1965 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Nevins, Allan, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - O'Connor, Raymong G., 1965 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, P-Z, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Ragland, James, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Rappaport, Armin, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Van Alstyne, R. W. - Department of History, USC, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, C-F, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - De Conde, Alex, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Freidel, Frank, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Franklin, William H. - State Department, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, D. C. Heath and Company, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Sortwell, Daniel R., 1965 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Quick, E. B., 1965 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, A-C, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Arbuckle, Ernest C., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Burton, Jack K., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, G-J, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Green, Walter J. - Editor, Appleton-Century-Crofts Company, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Gubser, Charles S. - United States Congressman, California, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Hamilton, Holman - Department of History, University of Kentucky, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, K-M, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Kennedy, Thomas - Department of History, University of Wyoming, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Leopold, Richard W., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Murphy, Paul L. - Department of History, University of Minnesota, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, M-P, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - McIluenna, Don - Oregon State University, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Nevins, Allen, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - O'Connor, Raymond G., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Q-S, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Quick, E. B., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Ragland, James T., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Rappaport, Armin, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Robinson, E. E., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Sterling, J. E. Wallace, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Sortwell, Daniel R., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, A-G, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - De Conde, Alex, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Green, Walter J., 1967 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, S-Z, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Tarr, Curtis W. - President, Lawrence University, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Van Alstyne, R. W., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Warren, Sidney - Department of History, California Western University, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, G-O, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Hamilton, Holman, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Kuchel, Thomas H., 1967 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Murphy, George, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - McIluenna, Don E. - Department of History, Oregon State University, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - O'Connor, Raymond G., 1967 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, P-Z, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Quick, E. B., 1967 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Rappaport, Armin, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Ragland, James, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Robinson, E. E., 1967 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Sortwell, Daniel R., 1967 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Senior Class Oration, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - History Department report, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 50th anniversity - panel discussions (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Books to order, 1941-1942 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Graduate study committee (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - History conference, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Newspapers (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Permissions, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Cornell correspondence re Russian book publication, 1950-1951 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence re czars and commissars (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Permissions, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence re The Pagent of the American People (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Departmental appointments, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence with Tarsaidze, Alexander (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Tressider correspondence re Northwestern offer, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Reviews of America Faces Russia (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Appleton-Century-Crofts, Inc., 1957 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Organization of the American Historians - Program Committee (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence with Aeschbacker, W. D. (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence with Aeschbacker, W. D. (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence with Hamilton, Holman (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence with Wiler, Allen of Appleton-Century Crofts, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Department annual reports, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, D. C. Heath and Company: The American Pageant (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, D. C. Heath and Company: The American Pageant (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence with Nobel, Bernard (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence with Treat, Winter (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - History department chairmanship, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Institute of American History, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence with Hughes, Stuart (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Pacific and Asiatic Studies Committee, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - International Relations Committee, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence with Naval Academy, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Question of German language requirement (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence with General Electric, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - "The Man in the Street" reviews, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Review of books, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence re The American Pageant, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence re Presidential address to Pacific Coast Branch of American Historical Association (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence with Linder, Dr. Doris (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Suggestions to new members of the History Department (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Army specialized training programs, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Book notices - miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - History for the Army, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Lectures at Harvard, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Army War College vouchers (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - European information tour, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Heath and Company - The American Pageant (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Heath and Company - The American Pageant (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Appleton-Century-Crofts Company, 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - "Woodrow Wilson and the Great Betrayal" miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - "Woodrow Wilson and the Great Betrayal" miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - "Woodrow Wilson and the Great Betrayal" miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - The American Pageant (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Revision of "Diplomatic History of the American People", 1945 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Liberal Arts program, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Staff status, Western Civilization, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Cost estimates for instructing 600 men in American History (Box 7)
  - Bailey-Buss correspondence (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Budget, 1952-1953 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence re borel collecting (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Entertaining, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Niegles Committee (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Promotions, 1952-1953 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - History Department report to President, 1953-1954 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Sabbaticals, 1952-1953 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Travel and expenses, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence and information re Lusitania sinking, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    Transferred to Hoover Institution Archives on 1975 August 27
  - Concerning 1924 Immigration Act data (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Publication lists of printing companies, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - "Cortia", 1952 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Remodeling of history corner, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Admissions to History Department, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Income tax, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Income tax, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Income tax, 1943 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Income tax, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Income tax, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Income tax, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Income tax, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Income tax, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Income tax, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Income tax, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Income tax, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Income tax, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Army training program - financial, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Institute of Military Studies (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Western Civilization Committee, 1952-1953 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Mississippi Valley Historical Association, 1962-1964 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence with Long, Ella, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - American Historical Association Nominating Committee, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence re a high school history text, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, Rappaport, 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence, Harcourt, Brace and Company, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence, D. C. Heath and Company, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence, D. C. Heath and Company, 1955-1958 (Box 8, Folder 38)
- Papers, 1963-1968; Series 2
  - The American Pageant, second edition manuscript (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The American Pageant, second edition manuscript (continued from Folder 1) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The American Pageant, third edition manuscript, second edition partial manuscript (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The American Pageant (continued from Folder 3) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The American Pageant (continued from Folder 4) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The American Pageant (continued from Folder 5) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The American Spirit, second edition corrected typwritten manuscript, chapters 48-50 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The American Spirit, galley proofs (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Diplomatic History of the American People, printer's copy from which galley set (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Diplomatic History of the American People (continued from Folder 9) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Essays Diplomatic and Undiplomatic, edited by Alex De Conde and Armin Rappaport (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Essays Diplomatic and Undiplomatic (continued from Folder 11) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bibliographic material: A history of History at Stanford 1932-1943; the Mythmakers of American History; the Stanford History Newsletter, Winter1967-1968; introduction to a speech by Mark Hatfield, March 1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bibliographic material: article from Stanford Observer, January 1967; information re T. A. Bailey book fund, comprehensive biographical report by Pearl Mendes, and miscellaneous biographical notations. Richard A. G???, "The Teachings and Writings of an American Diplomatic Historian, Thomas A. Bailey" (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Appleton-Century-Crofts correspondence (subsidiary to Meredith Press) concerning publication of Presidential Greatness and The Art of Diplomacy, April 1965 through November 1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Appleton-Century-Crofts correspondence (continued from folder 15) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1965 December-1968 March (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 1965 September-1968 November (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Incoming correspondence, A-E, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Bernstein, Bart, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Brucker, Herbert, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Thomas Y. Crowell Company, publishers, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - De Conde, Alexander, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Degler, Carl, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Donnelley, Dixon, Assistant Secretary of State, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Incoming correspondence, F-L, 1964-1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Franklin, William M., Department of State Foreign Relations Committee, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Gubser, Charles, U. S. House of Representatives, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Harmsworth Professorship, Oxford University, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Hatfield, Mark, U. S. Senate, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - International publishers, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - J. B. Lippincott Company, publishers, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Kuchel, Thomas H., U. S. Senate, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Incoming correspondence, Mc-P, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Murphy, George, U. S. Senate, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - O'Connor, Raymond G., Temple University, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - O'Grady, Joseph P., Society for Historians of American Foreign Relations, LaSalle College, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Potter, David M., 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Incoming correspondence, Q-Z, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Ragland, James, California State College at Long Beach, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Rappaport, Armin, UC Berkeley, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Robinson, Edgar Eugene, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Sterling, J. E. Wallace, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Wright, Gordon, 1963-1968 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Outgoing correspondence, 1963-1967 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Outgoing correspondence, 1968 and undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Bound Reprints (Box 3)